A Guide to the Papers of John Randolph of Roanoke, 1781-1860, [n.d.]
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
- Series I: Letters and Documents
  - J[ohn] R[andolph] to James Mercer Garnett, 1824 April 26, ALS, 1 p.; Barrow. #1883. (Box-folder 6:34)
  - James Mercer Garnett to Dr. [John] Randolph, 1824 April 30, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; Barrow. #1883. (Box-folder 6:35)
  - D[elia Forman] Bryan to John Randolph, 1824 May 7, ALS, 3 pp. on 1 l.; with attached address leaf; postmarked Savannah GA, May 9. Additional postmark most likely British, and an additional Liverpool stamp on address leaf. #3400. (Box-folder 6:36)
  - Richard Rush to John Randolph 1824 June 21, ALS, 2 p. on 1 l.; with an admittance card to the Bar of the House of Peers dated 1824 June 25. (Box-folder 6:36A)
    Rush thanks Randolph for his kind note and expressions of sympathy and hopes that he has not suffered any during his voyage.
  - John Randolph to Various, 1824 December 2--1831 February 19, ALS, 90 pp. on 90 l.; copies in unidentified hand. #3400. (Box-folder 6:37)
    1824 December 2 to B[etty] T[ucker] C[oalter]; 1824 December 18 to "My Dear Child"; 1825 [February] 14 to B[etty] T[ucker] C[oalter]; 1825 [July] 3 to Unidentified; 1825 July 27 to Unidentified; 1825 November 20 to B[etty] T[ucker] C[oalter]; 1825 November 22 to Unidentified; 1825 Sunday Morning to Unidentified; 1826 February 12 to Unidentified; 1826 March 25 to "My Dear Child"; 1827 January 12 to B[etty] T[ucker] C[oalter]; 1827 February 2 to B[etty] T[ucker] C[oalter]; 1828 January 2 to B[etty] T[ucker] C[oalter]; 1828 January 3 to H[enry] T[ucker]; 1828 January 8 to B[etty] T[ucker] C[oalter]; 1828 January 19 to Unidentified; 1828 January 21 to "My Dear Child"; 1828 February 1 to B[etty] T[ucker] C[oalter], answering an inquiry about a line from Milton; 1828 March 27 to B[etty] T[ucker] C[oalter]; 1828 March 30 to B[etty] T[ucker] C[oalter]; 1828 August 18 to Unidentified (possibly [Betty Tucker Coalter]); 1828 October 7 to B[etty] T[ucker] C[oalter]; 1828 October 10 to B[etty] T[ucker] C[oalter]; 1828 November 1 to B[etty] T[ucker] C[oalter]; 1828 November 28 to B[etty] T[ucker] C[oalter]; 1828 December 15 to B[etty] T[ucker] C[oalter]; 1828 December 25 to B[etty] T[ucker] C[oalter]; 1829 January 29 to B[etty] T[ucker] C[oalter]; 1829 February 18 to B[etty] T[ucker] C[oalter]; 1829 February 25 to B[etty] T[ucker] C[oalter]; 1830 April 5 to J[ohn] R[andolph] B[ryan] and E[lizabeth] T[ucker] B[ryan]; 1830 April 7 to J[ohn] Randolph B[ryan]; 1830 May 1 to Bet[ty Tucker Randolph]; 1830 August 1 to "My Dear Children"; 1830 November 13 to Unidentified; 1830 November 14 to "My Dear Child"; 1830 December 21-22 to "My Dearest Child"; 1830 December 26 (fragment) to [John Randolph Bryan] (Newspaper clipping of full letter glued to first page.); 1831 January 4 to E[lizabeth] T[ucker] C[oalter]; 1831 February 19 to Unidentified.
  - John Randolph to [James Mercer Garnett], 1824 December 5, ALS, 1 p.; Barrow. #1883. (Box-folder 6:38)
    Addressed to "My dear old friend."
  - Henry St. George Tucker to John Randolph, 1824 December 15, ALS, 1 p.; with attached address leaf; Barrow; postmarked Winchester VA, December 1[6];. #5161. (Box-folder 6:39)
  - James Mercer Garnett to Dr. [John] Randolph, 1824 December 21, ALS, 3 pp. on 1 l.; docketed; Barrow. #1883. (Box-folder 6:40)
  - John Randolph to James Mercer Garnett, 1824 December 26, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; Barrow. #1883. (Box-folder 6:41)
  - James Mercer Garnett to Dr. [John] Randolph, 1824 December 28, ANS, 1 p.; Barrow. #1883. (Box-folder 6:42)
  - John Randolph to James Mercer Garnett, 1824 December 31, ALS, 1 p.; Barrow. #1883. (Box-folder 6:43)
  - John Randolph Speech, [ca. 1824], AD, 5 pp. on 5 l.; incomplete. #8477. (Box-folder 6:44)
  - James Mercer Garnett to Dr. [John] Randolph, 1825 January 5, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; Barrow. #1883. (Box-folder 6:45)
  - James Mercer Garnett to Dr. [John] Randolph, 1825 January 10, ALS, 3 pp. on 1 l.; docketed; Barrow. #1883. (Box-folder 6:46)
  - John Randolph to J[ames] M[ercer] Garnett, [1825] January 28, ALS, 1 p.; Barrow. #1883. (Box-folder 6:47)
  - James Mercer Garnett to [John Randolph], 1825 January 30, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; Barrow. #1883. (Box-folder 6:48)
  - John Randolph to James Mercer Garnett, 1825 February 1, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; Barrow. #1883. (Box-folder 6:49)
  - John Randolph to John Randolph Bryan, [1825] February [2], ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; with separate address leaf, with wax seal; in mylar sleeve. #3400 (Box-folder 6:50)
  - James Mercer Garnett to Dr. [John] Randolph, 1825 February 7, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; Barrow. #1883. (Box-folder 6:51)
  - John Randolph to [James Barbour], 1825 February 19, AL, 1 p. #10310. (Box-folder 6:52)
    Letter in third person, asking the Secretary of War what his answer will be concerning "Mr. Francis H. Deane's" admission to the military academy.
  - F[rancis] W[alker] Gilmer to John Randolph, 1825 June 23, ALS, 3 pp. on 1 l.; with attached address leaf, with partial wax seal; postmarked [Richmond VA,] June 24. #737. (Box-folder 6:53)
  - B[enjamin] W[atkins] Leigh to John Randolph, 1825 July 4, ALS, 3 pp. on 1 l.; with attached address leaf; docketed; postmarked Richmond VA, July 4. #3339. (Box-folder 6:54)
  - John Randolph to James Mercer Garnett, 1825 August 6, ALS, 1 p.; Barrow. #1883. (Box-folder 6:55)
  - James Mercer Garnett to John Randolph, 1825 September 2, ALS, 3 pp. on 1 l.; with attached address leaf; Barrow; postmarked Richmond VA, September 8. #1883. (Box-folder 6:56)
  - John Randolph to J[ames] M[ercer] Garnett, 1825 September 26, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; Barrow. #1883. (Box-folder 6:57)
  - James Mercer Garnett to Dr. [John] Randolph, 1825 November 15, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; Barrow. #1883. (Box-folder 6:58)
  - James Mercer Garnett to Dr. [John] Randolph, 1825 December 12, ALS, 1 p.; Barrow. #1883. (Box-folder 6:59)
  - James Mercer Garnett to Dr. [John] Randolph, 1825 December 20, ANS, 1 p.; Barrow. #1883. (Box-folder 6:60)
  - John Randolph to James Mercer Garnett, 1825 December 27, ALS, 1 p.; Barrow. #1883. (Box-folder 6:61)
  - John Randolph to John Randolph Bryan, 1826 January 17, ALS, 1 p.; with separate address leaf. Brittle letter and address leaf in mylar sleeves. #3400. (Box-folder 6:62)
  - John Randolph to James Mercer Garnett, 1826 January 31, ALS, 1 p.; Barrow. #1883. (Box-folder 6:63)
  - John Randolph to Dr. [John] Brockenbrough, 1826 February 10, ALS, 4 pp. on 1 l.; with typed copy. #2118. (Box-folder 6:64)
  - John Randolph to James Mercer Garnett, 1826 February 20, ALS, 1 p.; with address on verso; Barrow. #1883. (Box-folder 6:65)
  - John Randolph to James Mercer Garnett, 1826 February 21, ALS, 1 p.; Barrow. #1883. (Box-folder 6:66)
  - James Mercer Garnett to Dr. [John] Randolph, 1826 February 26, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; Barrow. #1883. (Box-folder 6:67)
  - John Randolph to James Mercer Garnett, 1826 March 4, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; Barrow. #1883. (Box-folder 6:68)
  - John Randolph to John S. Skinner, [1826 March 30], ALS, 1 p.; with attached address leaf; docketed; postmarked Washington City, March 30. Merchant description glued to letter. #6645. (Box-folder 6:69)
  - John Randolph to Peachy R. Gilmer, 1826 April 14, AL, 2 pp. on 1 l.; with attached address leaf, with partial wax seal; signature on letter and on address leaf removed. #6489. (Box-folder 6:70)
  - John Randolph to John S. Skinner, 1826 April -, Tuesday, ALS, 1 p. Merchant description glued to letter. #6645. (Box-folder 6:71)
  - James Mercer Garnett to Dr. [John] Randolph, 1826 May 13, ALS, 1 p.; Barrow. #1883. (Box-folder 6:72)
  - St. George Coalter to John Randolph, 1826 May 18, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l. Brittle along old folds. #3400. (Box-folder 6:73)
  - John Randolph to Lt. Colonel [John] Wilson, 1826 September 21, ALS, 3 pp. on 1 l.; with attached address leaf, with wax seal; docketed. #10690. (Box-folder 6:74)
  - Mr. Maury to John Randolph, 1826 October 26, AN, 2 pp. on 1 l.; with attached address leaf. #4152. (Box-folder 6:75)
  - John Randolph to James Mercer Garnett, 1826 December 12, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; Barrow. #1883. (Box-folder 6:76)
  - John Randolph to James Mercer Garnett, 1826 December 24, ALS, 1 p.; Barrow. #1883. (Box-folder 6:77)
  - John Randolph to Thomas M[arsh] F[orman] Bryan, 1827 January 9, ALS, 1 p. With mounting tape and preservation tape on verso. #9371-t. (Box-folder 6:78)
  - John Randolph to James Mercer Garnett, 1827 January 10, ALS, 1 p.; Barrow. #1883. (Box-folder 6:79)
  - John Randolph to General John Floyd, 1827 January 31, AN, 1 p.; with attached address leaf. #4362. (Box-folder 6:80)
  - John Randolph to James Mercer Garnett, 1827 February 19, ALS, 1 p.; Barrow. #1883. (Box-folder 6:81)
  - John Randolph to James Mercer Garnett, 1827 February 27, ANS, 1 p.; Barrow. #1883. (Box-folder 6:82)
  - John Randolph to J[ohn] Randolph Bryan, 1827 April 25, ALS, 1 p.; with attached address leaf, with partial wax seal. #2097. (Box-folder 6:83)
  - James Mercer Garnett to Dr. [John] Randolph, 1827 June 18, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; Barrow. #1883. (Box-folder 6:84)
  - John Randolph to James Mercer Garnett, 1827 June 22, ALS, 1 p.; Barrow. #1883. (Box-folder 6:85)
  - John Randolph to James Mercer Garnett, 1827 July 19, ALS, 1 p.; Barrow. #1883. (Box-folder 6:86)
    The first portion written on 1827 July 19, and continued on 1827 July 23.
  - James Mercer Garnett to Dr. [John] Randolph, 1827 October 16, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; Barrow. #1883. (Box-folder 6:87)
  - John Randolph to James Mercer Garnett, 1827 November 26, ALS, 1 p.; Barrow. #1883. (Box-folder 6:88)
  - John Randolph to John Randolph Bryan, 1827 December 5, ALS, 1 p.; with attached address leaf, with partial wax seal; postmarked Washington City, December 5 and Savannah GA, December 15. #2118. (Box-folder 6:89)
  - John Randolph to Andrew Stevenson, 1827 December 12, AD, 1 p.; docketed. #6489. (Box-folder 6:90)
    Note on verso requesting to be excused from serving on the Committee of Ways and Means.
  - John Randolph to James Mercer Garnett, 1827 December 17, ANS, 1 p.; Barrow. #1883. (Box-folder 6:91)
  - John R. Clay to John Randolph, 1827 December 23, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; with attached address leaf, with wax seal; docketed. #3339. (Box-folder 6:92)
  - John Randolph to James Mercer Garnett, 1827 December 27, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; Barrow. #1883. (Box-folder 6:93)
  - [John Randolph] to [Mr. Hill], 1828 January 5, AN, 1 p. Brittle along old folds.#2832-a. (Box-folder 6:94)
  - John Randolph to Peyton Randolph, 1828 January 5, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l. Preservation tape along old brittle folds. #3579. (Box-folder 6:95)
  - James Mercer Garnett to [John Randolph], 1828 January 7, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; wax seal; Barrow. #1883. (Box-folder 6:96)
  - John Randolph to [Dr. John Brockenbrough], 1828 January 10, ALS, 1 p.; lower right corner torn away, affecting text; Barrow. #5995. (Box-folder 6:97)
    Handwritten notes possibly by Hugh A. Garland for his biography of John Randolph.
  - John Randolph to [James Mercer] Garnett, 1828 February 10, ANS, 1 p.; with partial address; Barrow. #1883. (Box-folder 6:98)
  - John Randolph to [Messrs. Fish and Grinnan], 1828 February 29, ALS, 3 pp. on 1 l. Brittle along fold. #9551-f. (Box-folder 6:99)
  - John Randolph to William H. Thompson, 1828 March 5, ALS, 1 p. #6489. (Box-folder 6:100)
  - J[ohn] Marshall to John Randolph, 1828 March 6, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; typescript copy only. #3408. (Box-folder 6:101)
  - Notes by John Randolph giving corrections for a copy of his 1828 February 1 Retrenchment speech, 1828 March 15, AN, 1 p. #4752. (Box-folder 6:102)
  - John Randolph to Harmanus Bleecker, 1828 March 17., ALS, 1 p. on 1 l.; with attached address leaf, with partial wax seal; docketed; postmarked Washington City, March 17. #3677. (Box-folder 6:103)
  - John Randolph to Mrs. [Stephen] Decatur (Susan Wheeler), 18[28] April 7, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; with typed transcript. #2279. (Box-folder 6:104)
  - John Randolph to Mrs. [Stephen] Decatur (Susan Wheeler), [1828] April 8, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; with typescript copy. Partially torn along old fold lines. #5108. (Box-folder 6:105)
  - John Randolph to John Brockenbrough, 1828 April 10, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; with attached address leaf; postmarked Washington City, April 10; Barrow. #5995. (Box-folder 6:106)
    A few pencil notes on the letter. Handwritten notes possibly by Hugh A. Garland for his biography of John Randolph.
  - Timothy Pickering to John Randolph 1828 April 12, ALS, 1 p. on 1 l. (Box-folder 6:106A)
    Notifies Randolph that he has sent a dozen copies of the first edition of his Review to a Baltimore bookseller, who would forward them on to Randolph in Washington. He also asks Randolph to do his best to defeat the Tariff of 1828 (the Tariff of Abominations) with its recent amendments, "kill the ravenous monster, whose voracity increases with what it feeds upon. It belongs not to a legislature to prescribe how individuals shall employ their heads, their hands, or their property, in the prosecution of their own chosen lawful occupations."
  - John Randolph to [James Mercer] Garnett, 1828 April 17, ALS, 1 p.; Barrow. #1883. (Box-folder 6:107)
  - William Leigh to [James Mercer Garnett], 1828 May 6, ANS, 1 p.; Barrow. #1883. (Box-folder 7:1)
    Mentions Randolph's illness, and the possibility that Randolph's speech on the Tariff will never be published.
  - John Randolph to John Brockenbrough, 1828 May 27, ALS, 4 pp. on 1 l. Pencil notes on letter; punched holes along left hand margin, partially affecting text. Handwritten notes possibly by Hugh A. Garland for his biography of John Randolph. #5995. (Box-folder 7:2)
  - John Randolph to John Brockenbrough, 1828 June 3, ALS, 1 p.; with attached address leaf; postmarked [Charlottesville] VA, June [?]. Pencil note "print" on letter; punch holes along left-hand margin, affecting text. Handwritten notes possibly by Hugh A. Garland for his biography of John Randolph. #5995. (Box-folder 7:3)
  - John Randolph to Thomas M[arsh] F[orman] Bryan, 1828 December 6, ALS, 1 p.; with attached address leaf, with partial wax seal; postmarked Washington City, December [6]? #6995. (Box-folder 7:4)
  - John Randolph to John Brockenbrough, 1828 December 7, ALS, 1 p. Punch holes down left hand margin of letter, not affecting text. Handwritten notes possibly by Hugh A. Garland for his biography of John Randolph. #5995. (Box-folder 7:5)
  - John Randolph to [John] Brockenbrough, 1828 December 22, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l. Pencil notes on letter; punched holes along left hand margin, partially affecting text. Handwritten notes possibly by Hugh A. Garland for his biography of John Randolph. #5995. (Box-folder 7:6)
  - John Randolph to James Mercer Garnett, 1828 December 22, ALS, 1 p.; Barrow. #1883. (Box-folder 7:7)
  - James Mercer Garnett to [John Randolph], 1828 December 26, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; Barrow. #1883. (Box-folder 7:8)
  - John Randolph to Mrs. Cooper, [ca. 1828] Wednesday, ALS, 1 p. Letter soiled, and with preservation taping. #3905. (Box-folder 7:9)
  - John Randolph to [John] Brockenbrough, 1829 January 8, ALS, 3 pp. on 1 l. Punched holes down left-hand margin of letter, not affecting text. Partially torn along old brittle folds. Handwritten notes possibly by Hugh A. Garland for his biography of John Randolph. #5995. (Box-folder 7:10)
  - John Randolph to John Brockenbrough, 1829 January 26, ALS, 1 p.; with attached address leaf; postmarked Washington City, January 26. Pencil note "print" on letter; punched holes down left-hand margin of letter, not affecting text. Handwritten notes possibly by Hugh A. Garland for his biography of John Randolph. #5995. (Box-folder 7:11)
  - John Randolph to John Brockenbrough, 1829 January 28, ALS, 1 p.; with attached address leaf; postmarked Washington City, January 28. With remnants of wax seal. Pencil note "print" on letter, with "Entire" crossed out. Punched holes down left-hand margin of letter, not affecting text. Handwritten notes possibly by Hugh A. Garland for his biography of John Randolph. #5995. (Box-folder 7:12)
  - John Randolph to John Brockenbrough, 1829 January 31, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; with attached address leaf; postmarked Washington City, January 31. With remnants of wax seal. Pencil note "print" on letter, with "Entire" crossed out. Punched holes down left-hand margin of letter, not affecting text. Handwritten notes possibly by Hugh A. Garland for his biography of John Randolph. #5995. (Box-folder 7:13)
  - John Randolph to J[ames] M[ercer] G[arnett], 1829 February 1, ALS, 1 p.; Barrow. #1883. (Box-folder 7:14)
  - John Randolph to Martin Van Buren, 1829 February 1, ALS, 3 pp. on 1 l.; with typed transcription; docketed in Martin Van Buren's hand. #6489, #3657. (Box-folder 7:15)
  - John Randolph to John Brockenbrough, 1829 February 6, ALS, 1 p.; with attached address leaf; postmarked Washington City, February 6. Pencil note "Entire" at top of letter. Punched holes down left-hand margin of letter, not affecting text. Handwritten notes possibly by Hugh A. Garland for his biography of John Randolph. #5995. (Box-folder 7:16)
  - John Randolph to John Brockenbrough, 1829 February 9, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l. Pencil note "Entire" on letter; Punched holes down left-hand margin of letter, not affecting text. Handwritten notes possibly by Hugh A. Garland for his biography of John Randolph. #5995. (Box-folder 7:17)
  - John Randolph to [John Brockenbrough], 1829 February 12, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l. Pencil note "Entire" on letter; Punched holes down left-hand margin of letter, not affecting text. Handwritten notes possibly by Hugh A. Garland for his biography of John Randolph. #5995. (Box-folder 7:18)
  - John Randolph to John Brockenbrough, 1829 February 16, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; with attached address leaf; postmarked Washington City, February 16. Pencil note "Entire" on letter; Punched holes down left-hand margin of letter, not affecting text. Handwritten notes possibly by Hugh A. Garland for his biography of John Randolph. #5995. (Box-folder 7:19)
  - E[lizabeth] T[ucker] C[oalter] to John Randolph, 1829 March 3, ALS, 3 pp. on 1 l.; with attached address leaf, with wax seal; docketed; annotations in unidentified hand. #3440-a. (Box-folder 7:20)
  - James Mercer Garnett to Dr. [John] Randolph, 1829 March 24, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; Barrow. #1883. (Box-folder 7:21)
  - John Randolph on "State's Rights," 1829 March 29, Ms, 2 pp. on 1 l.; Barrow. Note on verso. #5952. (Box-folder 7:22)
  - John Randolph to James Mercer Garnett, 1829 April 1, ALS, 1 p.; Barrow. #1883. (Box-folder 7:23)
  - John Randolph to John Brockenbrough, 1829 April 7, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; with attached address leaf; postmarked [Charlottesville] VA, April 10. Pencil note "Entire" on letter; Punched holes down left-hand margin of letter, not affecting text. Handwritten notes possibly by Hugh A. Garland for his biography of John Randolph. #5995. (Box-folder 7:24)
  - John Randolph to John Brockenbrough, 1829 April 21, ALS, 3 pp. on 1 l. Pencil note "Entire" on letter, postscript crossed out with "Omit" written across it; Punched holes down left-hand margin of letter, not affecting text. Handwritten notes possibly by Hugh A. Garland for his biography of John Randolph. #5995. (Box-folder 7:25)
  - Martin Van Buren to John Randolph, 1829 August 5, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; with separate address leaf; docketed; note on address leaf under the docket, "Sending English newspapers- The beginning of our correspondence."; postmarked Washington, August 6. #3339. (Box-folder 7:26)
  - Correspondence of John Randolph, 1829 September 16-1829 September 24, TL, copies, 2 pp. on 2 l.; typed copies. #2618. (Box-folder 7:27)
    Martin Van Buren to John Randolph, 1829 September 17, enclosing Andrew Jackson to John Randolph, 1829 September 16. John Randolph to Andrew Jackson, 1829 September 24.
  - John Randolph to Martin Van Buren, 1829 September 25, ALS, 1 p.; with attached address leaf; docketed. #8694-a. (Box-folder 7:28)
  - J[ohn] R[andolph] Bryan to John Randolph, 1829 November 1, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; with attached address leaf, with wax seal; docketed; postmarked Brooklyn NY, November 3. #2118. (Box-folder 7:29)
  - J[ohn] R[andolph] Bryan to John Randolph, 1829 November 12, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; with attached address leaf, with partial wax seal; docketed; postmarked Brooklyn NY, November 13. #2118. (Box-folder 7:30)
  - Bank Draft signed by John Randolph, 1830 January 16, ADS, 1 p. #9371-m. (Box-folder 7:31)
  - John Randolph Check to Chester Ringgold, 1830 January 16, ADS, 2 pp. on 1 l. #3440-a. (Box-folder 7:32)
  - J[ohn] R[andolph] Bryan to John Randolph, 1830 February 12, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; with attached address leaf, with wax seal; docketed; postmarked Fredericksburg VA, February 12. #2118. (Box-folder 7:33)
  - J[ohn] R[andolph] Bryan and E. T[udor] B[ryan] to John Randolph, 1830 March 23, ALS, 3 pp. on 1 l.; with attached address leaf, with partial wax seal; docketed; postmarked Savanna GA, March 24. #2118. (Box-folder 7:34)
  - John Randolph to Nathaniel Macon, 1830 April 28, L; typed transcription, with extracts of: (Box-folder 7:35)
    Martin Van Buren letter, 1830 February 25; Martin Van Buren to John Randolph, 1830 June 4, enclosing Andrew Jackson to John Randolph, 1830 June 3; Martin Van Buren letter to John Randolph, 1830 June 12; John Randolph to Nathaniel Macon, 1830 June 27. #2618.
  - John Randolph to Unidentified, 1830 July 27, ALS, 1 p.; docketed; with typed transcription. #8140. (Box-folder 7:36)
  - John Randolph to Mrs. Eliz[abeth] T[ucker (Coalter)] Bryan, 1830 September 2, 14, ALS, 2 pp on 1 l.; hole affecting text; docketed; with typed transcription. #3400. (Box-folder 7:37)
  - John Randolph to Louis McLane, 1830 October 31, ALS, 1 p.; with attached address leaf, with wax seal; docketed; postmark illegible. #7800. (Box-folder 7:38)
  - John Randolph to Thomas A. Morton, 1830 December 6, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l. #10392. (Box-folder 7:39)
  - J[ohn] R[andolph] Bryan to John Randolph, 1830 December 9, ALS, 3 pp. on 1 l.; with attached address leaf; docketed; postmarked Savannah GA, December 10. #2118. (Box-folder 7:40)
  - John Randolph to William Leigh, 1830 December 16, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l. Brittle; torn in half. #3339. (Box-folder 7:41)
  - John Randolph to Thomas Spring Rice, [ca. 1830?], ALS, 1 p. #9953. (Box-folder 7:42)
  - John Randolph to Daniel Webster, ca. 1831, 1888, ALS, 1 p. on 1 l. #10487. (Box-folder 7:43)
  - John Randolph to Lt. Col. [John] Wilson, 1831 February 1, ALS, 1 p. #10690. (Box-folder 7:44)
  - John Randolph to Benjamin W[atkins] Leigh, 1831 February 14, ALS, 1 p.; with separate address leaf, with partial wax seal; docketed; postmarked Washington, April 10. #8716. (Box-folder 7:45)
  - John Randolph to Walter Stirling, 1831 February 22, ALS, 1 p.; mounted. #9731-g. (Box-folder 7:46)
  - John Randolph to Ralph Randolph Wormiley, 1831 April 16, ALS, 1 p.; with attached address leaf; mounted; postmarked [London], 1831 April 16. #5842. (Box-folder 7:47)
  - John Randolph to Washington Irving, 1831 August 22, ALS, 1 p.; mounted. #2832. (Box-folder 7:48)
  - E[lizabeth] T[ucker (Coalter)] B[ryan] to John Randolph, 1831 October 5, ALS, 3 pp. on 1 l.; with attached address leaf, with wax seal; docketed; postmarked Gloucester VA, 1831 October 8. #49. (Box-folder 7:49)
  - [John Randolph] to J[ohn] R[andolph] B[ryan] and E. T[udor] B[ryan], 1831 October 18, AL, 1 p.; with attached address leaf; postmarked Baltimore MD, October 18. #2118. (Box-folder 7:50)
  - John Randolph to John Randolph Bryan and Eliz[abeth] T[ucker (Coalter)] Bryan, 1831 October 19, ALS, 1 p.; with attached address leaf. #2113. (Box-folder 7:51)
  - John Randolph to Mrs. [Elizabeth Tucker (Coalter)] Bryan, 1831 November 16, ALS, 3 pp. on 2 l.; with attached address leaf, with wax seal; postmarked Charlotte Court House VA, November 18; in mylar sleeve. #3400. (Box-folder 7:52)